finaldraft.com 2019-05-28

# Online Privacy Statement | Final Draft®

**Last updated   May 24, 2018.**

**Cast & Crew Global Privacy Statement**

Cast & Crew Services, LLC, together with our subsidiaries and affiliates (“Cast & Crew”) respects your privacy and is committed to protecting the personal information that you share with us, that is provided to us in connection with our products or services or that we otherwise receive. This Global Privacy Statement describes how we collect and use your personal information.

Protecting the privacy and security of this personal information is central to Cast & Crew’s mission. This Global Privacy Statement applies to all Cast & Crew entities and addresses the handling and treatment of your personal information. The Global Privacy Statement governs personal information collected by Cast & Crew for our own purposes as well as information provided to us as a data processor for our clients. It applies to information collected both online and offline.

Cast & Crew is also committed to transparency. We want individuals to understand how we collect and use personal information so they can interact with Cast & Crew with confidence. The information below covers how we collect, use, disclose, transfer, and store your information. Please take a moment to familiarize yourself with our privacy practices and if you have any questions, please contact us directly at Legal Department, Cast & Crew Services, LLC, 2300 Empire Avenue, 5th Floor, Burbank, CA 91504.

**_Information Collection (online & offline) _**

Personal information means any information that may be used to identify an individual, including, but not limited to, a first and last name, email address, a home, postal or other physical address, other contact information, title, birth date, gender, occupation, industry, personal interests, and other information when needed to provide a service you requested.  When ordering products on our website, you may be asked to provide credit card information. When you browse our website, you do so anonymously, unless you have previously indicated that you wish Cast & Crew to remember your login and password. We do not automatically collect personal information, including your email address. We do log your IP address (the Internet address of your computer) to give us an idea of which part of our website you visit and how long you spend there. We do not link your IP address to any personal information unless you have logged in to our website. Like many other commercial websites, the Cast & Crew website may use a standard technology called a “cookie” to collect information about how you use the site. Please go to “Cookies and Tracking Information” below for more information.

We collect personal information when you register with us for a Cast & Crew account, when you use certain Cast & Crew products or services, when you register to attend a seminar or participate in an online survey, when you ask to be included in an email or other mailing list, or when you submit your personal information to us for any other reason. We receive personal information from or on behalf of our clients in connection with our provision of products and services. We also receive personal information from business partners and vendors.

Access to certain Cast & Crew web pages may require a login and a password. The use of those web pages, and the information or programs downloadable from those pages, may be governed by a written agreement between your employer and Cast & Crew. Unless you request deletion of your personal information as specified below, your personal information may be retained by Cast & Crew to verify compliance with the agreement, log software licenses granted, to track software downloaded from those pages, or track usage of other applications available on those pages.

Cast & Crew will collect and process our clients’ and their employees’ personal information in accordance with the terms of our agreements with the client (the employer)  and applicable law. We will at all times maintain reasonable and appropriate security controls that are in alignment with industry related security frameworks to include HIPAA and the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) to protect your information.

Cast & Crew will only disclose personal information to the employer and to other entities in accordance with the terms of our agreements with the employer and applicable law. We may disclose your personal information to our affiliates and data processors as needed to provide the services that you and the employer have requested. These entities are all contractually bound to limit use of your personal information as needed to perform the services. We will also disclose personal information when required to do so by law, such as in response to a subpoena, including to law enforcement agencies and courts in the United States and other countries where we operate.

If you are based outside of the United States, your personal information may be transferred to Cast & Crew affiliates and data processers in the United States and elsewhere in the world. We will always protect the privacy and security of your personal information, regardless of where it is processed. Personal information transfers from the European Economic Area and other countries with data transfer restrictions will be authorized by approved model contract provisions or other appropriate means.

If you have questions about your privacy rights, please contact your employer’s human resources department. If you have questions about how Cast & Crew handles your personal information, you may contact us at Legal Department, Cast & Crew Services, LLC, 2300 Empire Avenue, 5th Floor, Burbank, CA 91504.

**_Right to Opt Out_**

You will always have the opportunity to “opt out” of receiving direct marketing or market research information. This means we assume you have given us your consent to collect and use your information in accordance with this Global Privacy Statement unless you take affirmative action to indicate that you do not consent.

**_Cookies and Tracking Technology  _**

A cookie is a small data file that certain websites write to your hard drive when you visit them. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID that the site uses to track the pages you have visited, but the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie cannot read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Some parts of Cast & Crew’s website use cookies to track user traffic patterns. We do this in order to determine the usefulness of our website information to our users and to see how effective our navigational structure is in helping users reach that information. If you prefer not to receive cookies while browsing our website, you can set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies and refuse the cookie when your browser alerts you to its presence. You can also refuse all cookies by turning them off in your browser, although you may not be able to take full advantage of our website if you do so. In particular, you may be required to accept cookies in order to complete certain actions on our website. You do not need to have cookies turned on, however, to use/navigate through many parts of our website, except access to certain of Cast & Crew’s web pages may require a login and password.

**_Information Sharing and Disclosure_**

Your personal information may be shared with Cast & Crew’s subsidiaries or affiliates. All such entities are governed by this Global Privacy Statement or are bound by the appropriate confidentiality and data transfer agreements.

Inside Cast & Crew, data is stored in controlled servers with limited access. Your information may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country where Cast & Crew, its subsidiaries, affiliates or agents are located.

We may send your personal information to other companies or people under the following circumstances: when we have your consent to share the information; we need to share your information to provide the product or service you have requested; we need to send the information to companies who work on behalf of Cast & Crew to provide a product or service to you (we will only provide those companies the information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose); or we want to keep you up to date on the latest product announcements, software updates, special offers or other information we think you would like to hear about either from us or from our business partners (unless you have opted out of these types of communications). We will also disclose your personal information if required to do so by law, to enforce our Terms of Use, or in urgent circumstances, to protect personal safety, the public or our websites.  Cast & Crew further reserves the right to create, utilize and share with third parties anonymized data which may be derived from personal information but does not contain an personally identifying information in its amalgamated form.

**_Data Security  _**

Your Cast & Crew account information, if applicable, is password-protected for your privacy and security. Cast & Crew safeguards the security of the data you send us with physical, electronic, and managerial procedures. In certain areas of our websites, we use industry-standard SSL-encryption to enhance the security of data transmissions. While we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure the security of the information you transmit to us, and so we urge you to take every precaution to protect your personal data when you are on the internet. Change your passwords often, use a combination of letters and numbers, and make sure you use a secure browser.

**_Software Piracy_**

We are committed to addressing and eliminating piracy or other misuse of our software and products.  As part of these efforts, we may include a security mechanism that can detect the installation or use of unauthorized or modified copies of our software and collect and transmit data about those copies.  This data collection is not designed to be performed on users of properly and legally licensed software obtained from us or our authorized resellers.  If you do not consent to the collection and transmission of such data (including to the United States), you must not use our software.

**_Access to Information  _**

We are dedicated to providing reasonable access to your personal information retained when you register with our website and correct any inaccuracies it may contain.  Registered users may access their user profile, correct and update their details, or unsubscribe at any time.  Registered users who have any problem accessing their profiles, or would like to request a copy of their personal information should contact Cast & Crew through the Contact Us link. In all cases we will treat requests to access information or change information in accordance with applicable law.

**_Children and Privacy  _**

Our websites do not target and are not intended to attract children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly solicit personal information from children under the age of 13 or send them requests for personal information.

**_Privacy Statement for Medical Records Processing Clients_**

Cast & Crew is committed to protecting the privacy and security of all personal information that we process in order to provide services to our clients in the healthcare industry. This notice explains our practices with regard to the protected health information we receive from our clients for medical records processing as a business associate under the US health privacy law known as HIPAA.

Cast & Crew will collect and process protected health information only as required or permitted by our services agreements and applicable law, including the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA). We will at all times maintain reasonable and appropriate security controls to protect the information as required by the HIPAA Security Rule.

If you have questions about privacy or security, please contact the HIPAA Privacy Official named in the Privacy Notice published by your healthcare provider or health insurance plan. If you have questions regarding how Cast & Crew handles your personal information, you may also contact us at Legal Department, Cast & Crew Services, LLC, 2300 Empire Avenue, 5th Floor, Burbank, CA 91504.

**_GDPR Privacy Statement_**

Cast & Crew abides by the EU GDPR regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information collected by organizations in the European Economic Area and Switzerland.  Cast & Crew certifies that it adheres to the GDPR as it applies to information collected and processed by Cast & Crew.

**_Social Security Number Protection Statement_**

Cast & Crew collects Social Security numbers and other sensitive personal information in the ordinary course of its business. We have implemented reasonable technical, physical and administrative safeguards to help protect the Social Security numbers and other sensitive personal information from unlawful use and unauthorized disclosure. All Cast & Crew associates, affiliates, suppliers and contractors are required to follow these established procedures, both online and offline.

Access to Social Security numbers is limited to those employees and contractors who have a need to access the information to perform tasks for Cast & Crew. Social Security numbers are only disclosed to third parties in accordance with Cast & Crew’s established privacy policies. We will only disclose Social Security numbers to those service providers, auditors, advisors, and/or successors-in-interest who are legally or contractually obligated to protect them or as required or permitted by law.

**_California Privacy Rights_**

California Civil Code Section 1798 allows California residents to ask companies with whom they have an established business relationship to provide certain information about the companies’ sharing of personal information with third parties for direct marketing purposes. Cast & Crew does not share any California consumer personal information with third parties for marketing purposes without consent.

California customers who wish to request further information about our compliance with this law or have questions or concerns about our privacy practices may contact us by writing to: Legal Department, Cast & Crew Services, LLC, 2300 Empire Avenue, 5th Floor, Burbank, CA 91504.

**_How Cast & Crew Uses Collected Information_**

Cast & Crew uses information for several general purposes: to fulfill requests for certain products and services, to provide services, including the display of content, to audit, research and conduct analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve our services, to ensure the technical functioning of our network, to protect the rights or property of Cast & Crew and our users, to develop new services, to personalize your experience on our website and to keep you up to date on the latest product announcements, software updates, special offers or other information we think you would like to hear about either from us or from our business partners. Subject to any applicable opt-in and opt-out requirements, Cast & Crew may also use your information to send, or to have business partners send, direct marketing information or contact our clients for market research.

**_Our Companywide Commitment to Your Privacy_**

To make sure your and your employees’ personal information is secure, Cast & Crew communicates its privacy and security guidelines to its employees and strictly enforces privacy safeguards within the company.

**_Changes to This Global Privacy Statement_**

Cast & Crew may amend this Global Privacy Statement from time to time to assure its consistency and adherence to applicable law. We will post any revised Global Privacy Statement on this site. You may raise any concerns regarding this Global Privacy Statement and our privacy practices using the contact information provided below and we will investigate and attempt to resolve any complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of personal information in accordance with applicable law. If you have questions, concerns or complaints about this Global Privacy Statement, please feel free to contact us any time through this website or at:

Legal Department

Cast & Crew Services, LLC  
2300 Empire Avenue 5th Floor  
Burbank, CA 91504-4603
